Benjamin Franklin Papers Part 1 -- Letters to Franklin 1730-1776 Mss.B.F85inventory01
American Philosophical Society
- Letters to Benjamin Franklin.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1776 Dec. 21, before 1777 Jan. 9]; Mem. 3p.; Barbeu-Dubourg, -----
    With reference to negotiations with the Farmers-General about a contract for supplying them with tobacco from Virginia.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1776?]; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Fergusson, W. Paris
    Congratulates Franklin on his arrival in Paris; desires to pay his respects and make a few domestic inquires.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1776?]; A.L.S. 1p.; Gadolle, -----
    Sending him a prospectus of his school.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1776?]; A.L.S. 1p.; Gadolle, -----. Bel-air
    Offers to take Franklin's two grandsons into his school.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1776]; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Vienne, Comte de (Field Marshal)
    Asking for a letter of introduction to General Washington for his son the Marquis de Vienne who has served for 20 years as officer in a regiment of dragoons.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1776?; L. 3p.; Williams, David
    Informs him of the great pleasure with which their Friendly Society heard his letter to him. Mr. Raspe, whom Franklin saw in Germany, joined the Society. Major Dawson, another member, is made Lieutenant Governor of the Isle of Man; rejoiced that the Major will not be called upon to fight the Americans. They consider all absent members as still belonging to their little club and cherish affection for them. Was exceedingly affected by the letter Congress sent to the people of England.
    (Torn.)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1766]; Priestley, Dr Joseph